<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper Research on Gavin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/series/paper-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper Research on Gavin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GavinSun0921&#34;&gt;Gavin Sun&lt;/a&gt;
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 13:53:33 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gavinsun0921.github.io/series/paper-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Breif Exploration to Variational Autoencoder (VAE) with Code Implementation</title>
      <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/paper-research-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 13:53:33 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/paper-research-02/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in the Paper Research series. In this series I will continue to update some personal study notes on reading papers. This post will introduce the basic work of variational autoencoder (VAE), including the derivation of formulas and simple code verification. Autoencoder Autoencoder is a neural network designed to learn an identity function in an unsupervised way to reconstruct the original input while compressing the data in the process so as</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Breif Exploration to Diffusion Probabilistic Models with Code Implementation</title>
      <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/paper-research-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:53:33 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/paper-research-01/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in the Paper Research series. In this series I will continue to update some personal study notes on reading papers. This post will introduce the basic work of diffusion probabilistic models (DPM), including the derivation of formulas and simple code verification. The content is mainly from Sohl-Dickstein et al. (2015) and Ho et al. (2020). If you have any suggestions on this post or would like to communicate with me, please leave comments below.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
