<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diffusion on Gavin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/tags/diffusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diffusion on Gavin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GavinSun0921&#34;&gt;Gavin Sun&lt;/a&gt;
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 13:53:33 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gavinsun0921.github.io/tags/diffusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Skim-read] Image Super-Resolution via Iterative Refinement</title>
      <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/fast-paper-reading-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 13:53:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/fast-paper-reading-02/</guid>
      <description>This paper is published in TPAMI 2023. Overview Problem In the field of image super-resolution, existing approaches often suffer from various limitations; e.g., autoregressive models are prohibitively expensive for high-resolution image generation, Normalizing Flows (NFs) and variational autoencoders (VAEs) often yield sub-optimal sample quality, and GANs require carefully designed regularization and optimization tricks to tame optimization instability and model collapse. Solution Present SR3, an approach to image super-resolution via repeated refinement based on DDPM. Results The high-frequency information of the image can be well resored compared to other methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Skim-read] Deblurring via Stochastic Refinement</title>
      <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/fast-paper-reading-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 13:53:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/fast-paper-reading-01/</guid>
      <description>This paper is published in CVPR 2022. Overview Problem Image deblurring is an ill-posed problem, and most existing mothods are ineffective because they produce a deterministic estimate of the clean image. Point-estimators that directly minimize a distortion loss suffers from the problem of &amp;ldquo;regression to the mean&amp;rdquo;. Solution Present a new framework for blind deblurring based on conditional diffusion models. Porducing a diverse set of plausible reconstructions for a given input. Results A significant improvement in perceptual qulity over existing state-of-the-art methods across multiple standard benchmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Breif Exploration to Diffusion Probabilistic Models with Code Implementation</title>
      <link>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/paper-reading-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:53:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gavinsun0921.github.io/posts/paper-reading-01/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in the Paper Reading series. In this series I will continue to update some personal study notes on reading papers. This post will introduce the basic work of diffusion probabilistic models (DPM), including the derivation of formulas and simple code verification. The content is mainly from [1,2]. If you have any suggestions on this post or would like to communicate with me, please leave comments below.
Diffusion Models What are Diffusion Models?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
